# **///// BIO**

Jonathan Berger is a designer, developer and technologist who has been active in the NYC technology community since 2005, helping to build products, teams, and events. He is an internationally sought speaker who talks about startups, technology, Lean, Agile, and product design.

## **SELECTED WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Chief Product Officer, Let The Music Pay, global / remote, 2021-present

We're building RCRDSHP, the Next Format in recorded music: digital collectibles on the Flow blockchain. I partner with engineering and oversee all aspects of digital product design, game design, collectible design, community, for both consumer- and creator-platforms, and help to hire and build the team.

### Director of Design Strategy, Fractal Technology Labs, NY, NY 2020-2021

Led the design strategy practice and helped build the New York office of a growing agile consultancy. Drove recruitment and business development, as well as leading design and product client work.

#### Consultant, NY, NY 2019-2020

Coached companies, led workshops, and developed curriculum and practice in product, design, and agile. Led teams and acted as product owner and designer on a variety of projects.

#### VP Product Coaching, Capital One, NY, NY 2017-2019

Helped build a Product Coaching practice in the Innovation team to lead a Digital Transformation in the Commercial Bank. I ran a team of coaches, organized trainings and conferences, and still managed to design, code, and coach as much as possible.

#### VP Product, Thrive Global, NY, NY 2016-2017

Guided practice and product among a portfolio of front- and back-end web apps, apps for iOS, Android, Alexa (and others!) for Arianna Huffington's post-Huffington Post media / wellness / product venture.

#### Consultant, NY, NY 2015-2016

Coached companies to use design and agile practices, via concrete outcomes and deliverables, to adapt to the changing realities of their business and the market.

#### Associate Director of Product Design, Pivotal Labs, NY, NY 2008-2015

Built and led a team of  $\sim 10$  designers, building an agile design practice and methodology. Built web and mobile apps using Agile, XP, and Test-Driven methodologies. At Pivotal I've also been a Designer, Engineering Manager, and Design Manager.

# **SKILLS**

Expert in Agile, Lean Startup, and Extreme Programming (XP) methodologies. Experienced product designer (desktop and mobile, web 2.0 and web3), with a strong emphasis on design systems and org design. Experienced with modern development tools including Ruby, Javascript, HTML, CSS, (including frameworks like Rails, React, Node, Express, SASS, and many more) and shell scripting. Extremely high level of proficiency in Vim, Adobe Creative Suite, Figma, and many more.

# **EDUCATION**

New School University, NY, NY Master of Arts in Media Studies

Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, NY Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy

# ### PUBLIC SPEAKING, REFERENCES, & CODE.

Portfolio of talks at http://www.jonathanpberger.com/talks, writings at jonathanpberger.com/blog, and references & portfolio available upon request. Code lives at http://github.com/jonathanpberger.